#### ADIT SHAH

San Ramon, CA 94582

(925) 997-9055 • aditshah00@gmail.com • http://www.linkedin.com/in/aditshah00 • https://github.com/ashah03

**SUMMARY** 

High school student passionate about driving positive societal change using computer science, machine learning, and robotics. My current areas of interest include research in multi-robot systems for natural disasters, and the

applications of machine learning to social justice and medical diagnostics.

**SKILLS** 

Programming: Python, Java, Kotlin, C/C++, MATLAB

Machine Learning: Neural Networks, Random Forest, Clustering, TensorFlow, Keras, YOLO, Object detection,

Robotics: ROS, gRPC, Gazebo, LIDAR, Autonomous operations, NVIDIA Jetson TX2

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Summer 2019

Research Mentorship Program, University of California, Santa Barbara, CA Improving the Efficiency and Scalability of Multi-Drone Coverage Systems with Decentralized Control (mentored by Bryce Ferguson, PhD Student at UCSB)

- One of 75 high-school students from around the world chosen for graduate-level research
- Developed and simulated decentralized algorithms in MATLAB for multi-drone coverage systems for applications in mapping, disaster prevention and assessment, and environmental monitoring
- Authored an academic research paper, delivered a 10-minute symposium talk, and participated in a poster session

#### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

April 2018

Robolink (Robotics Education Company), San Diego, CA

- January 2019 Software Development Intern
  - Developed software for Zümi, a new CES award-winning robotics kit
  - Developed Machine Learning demos and optimized these demos on the Raspberry Pi for Zümi
  - Ran Robolink's San Diego Maker Faire booth, presented ML demo, and marketed products and classes

& 2017

Summer 2018 Avi Networks (Software Load Balancing and Web Application Firewall), Santa Clara, CA

- Software Development Intern
- Developed a Machine Learning proof of concept for WAF (Web Application Firewall) product using Neural Networks, Random Forest, and Clustering algorithms
- Developed automation software in Python and Ansible for testing the Avi Vantage Platform on Cisco CSP 2100, reducing end-to-end testing cycle on this platform from hours to minutes

### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

July 2019 -

Tenderloin Technology Lab, St. Anthony Foundation, San Francisco, CA

Present

Tutor, Guest Assistant, Workshop Volunteer

- Volunteer at the Tenderloin Technology Lab, a free technology training center and computer lab located in the Tenderloin, San Francisco's poorest district, to provide vulnerable residents with basic technology skills
- Help people in the local community apply for jobs, format resumes, and provide general technical support
- Work with guests 1-on-1 to help demystify technology, and help teach computer and smartphone workshops

### **ACTIVITIES & INITIATIVES**

2017-Present: Athenian WiSE, The Athenian School

Co-Founder & Board Member

- Founded WiSE (Women in Science and Engineering) a gender-diversity STEM initiative
- Run an annual hands-on STEM event that attracts 200+ people now in its 3<sup>rd</sup> iteration

2017-Present: FRC Team 852, The Athenian School

Programming Lead & Executive Board Member, Member Training Lead, Operations Lead

- Member of executive board, which includes 6 students team mentors, and has final say on all team decisions
- Responsible for all programming on the robotics team, including robot driver-control, autonomous, and team apps
- Responsible for organizing all pre-season team training, develop curriculum and teach programming sessions
- Oversee team operations (non-robot) tasks, including outreach and competition logistics
- 7<sup>th</sup> year of robotics (including FRC, VEX Robotics attended World Championships twice, and FLL)

2017-Present: Entrepreneurship, The Athenian School

- Developed idea for a software platform to diagnose autism by applying Machine Learning to EEG data
- Won the Northern California division of the Diamond Challenge, a global entrepreneurship competition

2018-Present: Physics Teaching Assistant, The Athenian School

Grade homework assignments, lab reports, quizzes, and tests; tutor students 1-on-1 and hold office hours

2019-Present: Student Teaching & Learning Committee, The Athenian School

Working with the Director of Teaching and Learning to revamp the school's 6<sup>th</sup> to 12<sup>th</sup> grade science curriculum to bring it in line with the NGSS standards and add an honors science program

### **EDUCATION**

2017-Present: The Athenian School (High School), Danville, CA GPA: 4.45

AP Comp Sci (5), AP Calc AB (5), AP Calc BC, Data Structures & Algorithms, Physics, Biology, Advanced Chemistry

Other Activities: Math Club (Co-Founder)

2017-2018: Coursera Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng

• TensorFlow • Keras • Neural Networks • Hyperparameter tuning and optimization • Data collection

• Structuring Machine Learning Projects • Convolutional Neural Networks • Recurrent Neural Networks

# <u>AWARDS</u>

Feb. 2020	Dean's List Semifinalist, First Robotics Competition
Nov. 2019	Meritorious, High School Mathematical Contest in Modeling (HiMCM)
Nov. 2018	<b>3<sup>rd</sup> Place,</b> SMHacks (High School Hackathon)
Feb. 2018	Northern California Winner, Diamond Challenge

Apr. 2016 **2<sup>nd</sup> Place**, Alameda County Science and Engineering Fair